AMAN GOEL

Ph.D. Candidate, Computer Science & Engineering, University of Michigan

Basic Information 5^{th} Year Ph.D. Candidate (adviser: Prof. Karem Sakallah) Formal Methods & Automated Reasoning Group, CSE University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, USA $amangoel@umich.edu +1 (734) 881-0674 \\ aman-goel.github.io$

という

RESEARCH Interests My research interests include exploring reliability & security of complex systems, and developing automated reasoning algorithms for ensuring system correctness. I also have a developing interest in data structures & algorithms, programming languages, machine learning and web systems. My current work focuses on automatic verification of complex systems.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, USA

Aug 2016 - Present

Ph.D. student, Computer Science & Engineering Grade Point Average: 3.96/4

IIT Madras, India

July 2011 - May 2016

Silver Medalist

 $Bachelor\ of\ Technology,\ Electrical\ Engineering\ Master\ of\ Technology,\ Microelectronics\ \&\ VLSI$

- Grade Point Average: 9.23/10

- Minor: Industrial Engineering (GPA: 9.33/10)

RECENT RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

\bigcirc Developer of AVR

Sep 2016 - Present

AVR is a tool for automatic verification of state-transition systems

- Successfully applied on hardware and software systems
- Uses SMT solvers to perform word-level formal verification
- Uses data abstraction for scaling unbounded property verification
- Won 1^{st} place in the prestigious Hardware Model Checking Competition (HWMCC) 2020

• Developer of I4

Aug 2018 - Present

I4 is a tool for automatic, push-button verification of distributed systems

- Performs automated correctness checking and bug-hunting for distributed systems
- Uses formal methods and symmetry to simplify and automate verification tasks

Contributor to Open-source Tools

Summer 2020 @ Menlo Park, CA

Yices 2

- A state-of-the-art SMT solver from SRI
- Worked with the CSL team and developed techniques for quantified SMT solving

Contributor to Commercial Tools

Summer 2019 @ Haifa, Israel

JasperGold

- A state-of-the-art formal verification platform from Cadence
- Developed word-level verification engines for JasperGold
- Worked with Cadence SVG (systems verification group) and developed algorithms for automatically solving hard verification tasks

RECENT SERVICE Artifact evaluation committees (AEC)

2019 - Present

VMCAI'21: Conference on Verification, Model Checking, and Abstract Interpretation OOPSLA'20: Conference on Object-Oriented Programming Systems, Languages, and Apps CAV'20: Conference on Computer-Aided Verification

SKILLS

Good knowledge of C++, C, Python, Verilog, Shell scripting Working knowledge of MATLAB, Java, HTML, LLVM Good understanding of SAT / SMT solvers

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- AVR: Abstractly Verifying Reachability

 Aman Goel, and Karem Sakallah. In International Conference on Tools and Algorithms for the Construction and Analysis of Systems (TACAS), 2020 (to appear).
- L4: Incremental Inference of Inductive Invariants for Verification of Distributed Protocols Ma, Haojun, Aman Goel, Jean-Baptiste Jeannin, Manos Kapritsos, Baris Kasikci, and Karem A. Sakallah. In Proceedings of the 27th Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP), ACM, 2019.
- Towards Automatic Inference of Inductive Invariants

 Ma, Haojun, Aman Goel, Jean-Baptiste Jeannin, Manos Kapritsos, Baris Kasikci, and Karem

 A. Sakallah. In Proceedings of the Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS), pp. 30-36. ACM, 2019.
- Model checking of Verilog RTL using IC3 with syntax-guided abstraction Aman Goel, and Karem Sakallah. In NASA Formal Methods Symposium (NFM), pp. 166-185. Springer, Cham, 2019.
- Empirical evaluation of IC3-based model checking techniques on Verilog RTL designs
 Aman Goel, and Karem Sakallah. In 2019 Design, Automation & Test in Europe Conference
 & Exhibition (DATE), pp. 618-621. IEEE, 2019.
- iitRACE: A memory efficient engine for fast incremental timing analysis and clock pessimism removal

 Peddawad, Chaitanya, Aman Goel, B. Dheeraj, and Nitin Chandrachoodan. In 2015 IE-EE/ACM International Conference on Computer-Aided Design (ICCAD), pp. 903-909. IEEE, 2015.

Honors & Awards

- Recipient of Rackham Predoctoral Fellowship 2020-21 for outstanding PhD research
- Runner-up finalist of the CSE Graduate Student Honors Competition 2019 for outstanding PhD research for Push-button Verification using Abstraction and Induction
- Recipient of Dwight F. Benton fellowship at University of Michigan for 2016-17
- Recipient of research travel grant and Israel travel award for 2019
- Branch position 2 in Electrical Engineering at IIT Madras (Silver medalist)
- Won international 3rd place in TAU Contest at ICCAD 2015 for Incremental Timing Analysis
- Recipient of best undergraduate research project at Pan IIT Research Expo 2014
- Recipient of *Electronics for You* prize for best academic performance at graduate level
- Won $\it National~Award$ for the Empowerment of Persons with Disabilities 2013 for Solar Charger for Hearing Aid Devices

Selected Courses

University of Michigan

- Advanced Algorithms
- Advanced Compilers
- Formal Verification

- $AI\ Foundations$
- Web Systems

IIT Madras

Computer Science:

Aman Goel 2 / 3

- Computational Engineering - Digital Systems Testing Mathematics & Operations Research: - Combinatorial Optimization - Probability Foundations - Fundamentals of Operational Research - Decision Modelling Teaching University of Michigan: EXPERIENCE EECS 281 Data Structures & Algorithms Aug - Dec 2017 & 2018 EECS 478 Logic Synthesis & Optimization Jan - Apr 2018 EECS 579 Digital System Testing Aug - Dec 2019 EECS 492 Introduction to Artificial Intelligence Jan - Apr 2020 IIT Madras: EE 5311 Digital IC Design Aug - Nov 2015 EE 5332 Mapping Signal Processing Algorithms to DSP Architectures Jan - May 2016 Former - Summer School on Formal Techniques Summer 2018 @ Menlo Park, CA ACTIVITIES Invited participant at Summer School on Formal Techniques 2018 hosted by SRI - MPUC: Compiler for Memristor Arrays Jan - Apr 2017 Developed a compiler for coarse-grained architecture of memristor arrays - Radiation Pattern Measurement System for Automotive Radar May - July 2014 Wireless Connectivity Solutions, Texas Instruments, India Developed an automatic radar positioning system for radar modules testing Voice to Text Converter Mar 2013 Developed software that converts voice input in a language to text field in other chosen language using available softwares of Google Voice Recognition and Google Translate OTHERS - U-M Mentorship program 2016 - Present Encourage and guide undergraduate students towards CS major, programming and graduate studies Voluntary blood donor Hobbies Swimming, Water Polo, Skating (ice & roller), Soccer

- Data Structures & Algorithms

Aman Goel 3 / 3

- Design Verification